By now, you should be aware
that effective team communication
is necessary to help ensure a
successful project outcome.
In this video, I'll share
more tips for communicating
with your team and
introduce you to tools
that will help you and
your team communicate
even more effectively.
As the project manager,
you are the one who connects
your team to the
information they need.
Throughout the project, you'll
serve as the main resource for
your team when it comes to
communicating and
clarifying goals,
action items,
progress, and updates.
It's important to make sure that
you are carrying
information forward
consistently and coherently
so that everyone
understands what the
current state of
the project is and
what happens next.
Teams communicate in
a myriad of ways.
Though project managers
are constantly
communicating through
check-ins and meetings,
project documents such as
project plans
including schedules,
trackers, and meeting notes,
they're also hubs for
team communication.
It's your responsibility
to be clear
about how those
documents get used,
who has access to
those documents,
and how often the
documents get updated.
Of course, in addition to
those responsibilities,
you'll also have to field e-mails,
instant messages,
and attend meetings.
All of these things are critical
in driving a project forward.
As a project manager,
you are the one who coordinates
incoming and outgoing
information.
You connect individuals to
the necessary details and
context and track who
needs to receive what
information and when.
You'll need to communicate
certain information
to your team multiple
times and in various ways.
Some people learn by listening,
some people learn by watching,
and others learn by doing.
Communicating in various ways
ensures that you're
sharing knowledge to
your team in a format that's
digestible and easy
for them to take in.
Your team will have a lot
of tasks to focus on.
Be proactive and reinforce
important information
multiple times,
in multiple ways so that no
one is left out of the loop.
There are many tools for
communicating with your
team to make it easy to
keep in contact and be on
the same page throughout the
duration of the project.
Some of these include:
e-mail and messaging,
in-person meetings,
video conferencing,
and work management and
collaboration tools.
Your organization might have
some of these tools
in place already,
or you might have
the opportunity to
select some for a project.
In either case, it's good to be
familiar with what's out there.
We'll explore tools that provide
effective project
team communication in
more detail in the next
video. Meet you there.